A Guide to the Virginia Genealogical Society Records, 1960-2015
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Genealogical Society Records, 1960-2015
The Library of Virginia
51827
10 cubic feet (22 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Virginia Genealogical Society, Orange.
Historical Information
The Virginia Genealogical Society was founded in 1960 to promote, perpetuate, foster, and encourage interest in genealogical, historical, biographical, and heraldic research, and to publish information relating to genealogy, as well as participate in the search for manuscripts, documents, and records pertaining to genealogy which have not been accessible, thereby ensuring their preservation and publication. The Society also shares with others the skills, techniques, knowledge, procedures, and methods involved in genealogical research.
Scope and Content
Records, 1960-2015, of the Virginia Genealogical Society, including awards program nominations, Board of Governors meeting agendas and minutes, conference materials, constitutions and bylaws, correspondence, financial records, grant files, membership lists, publication and project files, copies of the Quarterly Bulletin and Newsletter, and scrapbooks.
Contents List
- Advertising/Publicity. (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Ancestry.com - Magazine on CD. (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Archive CD Books. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Awards Program, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Awards Program Nominations. (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Bank Statements, 2008-2009. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- BITNET. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Board Agendas, 1998-2009. (Box 1, Folder 11-22)
- Board Agendas, 2010-2015. (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
- Board Minutes, 1960-1979. (Box 2, Folder 7-16)
- Board Minutes, 1980-2015. (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
- Bowry, J. Philip III. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Budget Reports, 1994-2015. (Box 3, Folder 10-16)
- Bierne Carter Foundation. (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
- Bierne Carter Foundation Grant Proposal. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Cash in Bank, 2008-2009. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Catering. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Certificates/Awards. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Check Register, 2008-2009. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Circuit Court Records Preservation Program. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Clay Fund. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Constitutions and Bylaws. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Correspondence (Pippenger, Wesley E.). (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Corresponding Secretary, 1960-1964. (Box 4, Folder 13-17)
- Corresponding Secretary, 1965-1967. (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
- Credit Card Worksheets, 2008-2009. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- "The Czech Community in Hanover County" by S.L Rada 2001. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Danka. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Death Notices from Richmond, Virginia Newspapers, 1841-1853. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Death Records Indexing Project (DRIP). (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Donations/Bequests. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Earnings Records, 2008-2009. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- The Effects of the French and Indian War on Civilian Life in the Frontier Counties of Virginia, 1754-1763. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Fall Conference, 1989. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Fall Conference, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Fall Conference, 1992. (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Fall Conference, 1993. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Fall Conference, 1995. (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Fall Conference, 1997. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Fall Conference, 1999-2002. (Box 5, Folder 20-23)
- Fall Conference, 2003-2009. (Box 6, Folder 1-12)
- Fall Conference, 2012-2014. (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
- Family History Month, 1997. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Federation of Genealogical Societies - VGS Sales, 2004-2008. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Financial Reports, 2008-2015. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Flyers. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- GiveRichmond/Community Foundation. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- A Goodly Heritage by Dr. B. Noland Carter. (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
- A Goodly Heritage - Orders. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Grants. (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
- Grant Applications, 2000-2001. (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
- Grant Applications, 2000-2001. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Grant Program, 1999-2000. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Grant Proposals by VGS, 1984. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- GRIVA. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Guide to Research Facilities, Societies, and Organizations. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Hanover Historical Commission - Interviews by Alden Aaroe, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Index to Death Notices. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Index to Virginia Estates, 1800-1865. (Box 8, Folder 9-12)
- Investments. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Itemized Categories, 2008-2009. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Journal Entries, 2008-2009. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Leases. (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Ledger, 1980-1991. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Legislation. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Letters to the Editor. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Logo. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Lucas, Rev. Silas Emmett Jr. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Magazine. (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
- Magazine - Expenses. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Mailing Lists. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Marriage and Death Notices in Richmond, Virginia Newspapers, 1821-1840. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Marriage Notices From Richmond, Virginia Newspapers, 1841-1853. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Matching Grants to Support Archival Programs. (Box 9, Folder 11-14)
- Meetings Committee/James Bagby, 1987-1991. (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- Member Relations. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Membership Lists, 1974-1979. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Membership List, 1989. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Membership List, 1994. (Box 10, Folder n/a)
- Membership/Guest Lists. (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
- Membership/Guest Lists. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- "Memories of Montpelier" by M. Carlton Harris. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- "Midlothian" by William C. Wooldridge. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Move to 5001 W. Broad St., 1993. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- National Genealogical Society - Conference in the States, Richmond, 12-15 May 1999. (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
- National Genealogical Society - Conference in the States, Richmond, 16-19 May 2007. (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
- National Genealogical Society - Conference in the States - VGS Sales, 2003-2008. (Box 11, Folder 9-10)
- National Genealogical Society - Family History Conference, Richmond, 7-10 May 2014. (Box 11, Folder 11)
- National Genealogical Society Newsletter Competition. (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
- National Park Service Challenge Share Cost Program. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Newsletter, 1973-1978, 1980-1995. (Box 12, Folder 2-23)
- Newsletter, 1996-2007. (Box 13, Folder 1-12)
- Newsletter, 2008-2015. (Box 14, Folder 1-8)
- Nominations, 2000-2001. (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Officers and Committee Chairs. (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Operating Fund/Account Balances, 2008-2009. (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Pippenger, Wesley E., 1995-1997. (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
- Planned Giving Committee. (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Planned Giving Committee - President's File. (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Plaque - National Genealogical Society Honorary Institutional Member, 1999. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Position Descriptions. (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Position Descriptions - Executive Director. (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
- Proclamation - City of Newport News, 2008. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Projects. (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Project Support. (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Publication Policy. (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Publications. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Publications - Book Orders. (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Publications - Free Offer to Libraries, 2009. (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Quarterly Bulletin, 1963-1965. (Box 15, Folder 15-17)
- Quarterly Bulletin, 1966-1967. (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
- Quarterly Bulletin - Index, 1963-1967. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Quarterly Bulletin and Index, 1968-1970. (Box 16, Folder 4-6)
- Queries. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Questionnaires/Surveys. (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Records Retention Policy/Insurance. (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Researchers. (Box 16, Folder 10)
- RoweCom Bankruptcy. (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Sales at Other Conferences, 2004-2008. (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Sales Tax Deposits/Payments, 2008-2009. (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Scrapbook, 1960-1973. (Box 21, Folder 1-7)
- Scrapbook, 1974-1987. (Box 22, Folder 8-13)
- Scrapbook pages, 1978-1995. (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Seal. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Slides. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- "Some Superstitions of Our Ancestors". (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Southern Claims Commission Project. (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Southern Claims Commission Project - Impact Manager. (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Special Grant Program. (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
- Spring Conference, 1971. (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Spring Conference, 1989-1996. (Box 17, Folder 5-12)
- Spring Conference, 2000-2005. (Box 17, Folder 13-23)
- Spring Conference, 2006-2015. (Box 18, Folder 1-11)
- Statistics. (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Strays Project. (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Surname Exchange. (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
- Sweeney, Alice. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Taxes, 2008-2009. (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Thank Yous. (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Treasurer's Reports. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Vendors. (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Virginia Atlas and Gazetteer, 1989. (Box 20, Folder n/a)
- Virginia Institute of Genealogical Research, 5-9 August 2001. (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Virginia Institute of Genealogical Research, 6-10 July 2003. (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Virginia Institute of Genealogical Research, 1-5 August 2004. (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
- Virginia Institute of Genealogical Research, 31 July - 4 August 2005. (Box 19, Folder 12)
- VLA Scholarship. (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Virginia Transportation Research Council - Road Order Books. (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
- Vital Records. (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Website. (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Witt, Peter. (Box 19, Folder 18)